<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.eclipse.org/projects/project-plan.xsl"?>
<!--<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="project-plan-render.xsl"?>-->
<plan plan-format="1.0" xmlns="http://www.eclipse.org/project/plan" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      name="MoDisco (Model Discovery)">
   <release projectid="modeling.mdt.modisco" version="0.10.0"/>
   <introduction>
     <html:div>
     	This document lays out the feature and API set for the next release of the Eclipse MoDisco framework (MDT MoDisco Project), version 0.10.0.
     	This project plan inherits from the Modeling Project Plan, which should be referenced when consulting this individual project plan.
     </html:div>
   </introduction>
   <release_deliverables>
     <html:div>
     	The release deliverables have the same form as is found in most Eclipse projects, namely:
     	<html:ul>
     		<html:li>MDT MoDisco SDK (includes runtime, sources, examples, tests and documentation) (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
     		<html:li>MDT MoDisco runtime binary distribution (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
     		<html:li>MDT MoDisco documentation (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
     		<html:li>MDT MoDisco examples (downloadable).</html:li>
     	</html:ul>
     	Note that Eclipse MDT MoDisco 0.10.0 will primarily target Eclipse 3.8 and be tested against Eclipse 4.2.
     </html:div>
   </release_deliverables>
   <release_milestones>
      <preamble>
         <html:div>
         	Release milestones occur at roughly 6 week intervals and follow the Platform milestone releases by approximately 1 week; that is, until the final 3.8 and 4.2 releases of the Platform, upon which MDT MoDisco and other projects will release simultaneously. 
         	As MDT MoDisco depends on other projects, it will deliver its milestones at the +3 schedule in accordance with the schedule below. 
         </html:div>
      </preamble>
      <milestone date="08/17/2011" milestone="M1"></milestone>
      <milestone date="09/28/2011" milestone="M2"></milestone>
      <milestone date="11/09/2011" milestone="M3"></milestone>
      <milestone date="12/14/2011" milestone="M4"></milestone>
      <milestone date="02/01/2012" milestone="M5"></milestone>
      <milestone date="03/21/2012" milestone="M6"><html:b>(API Freeze)</html:b></milestone>
      <milestone date="05/09/2012" milestone="M7"><html:b>(Feature Freeze)</html:b></milestone>
      <milestone date="05/23/2012" milestone="RC1"></milestone>
      <milestone date="05/30/2012" milestone="RC2"></milestone>
      <milestone date="06/06/2012" milestone="RC3"></milestone>
      <milestone date="06/13/2012" milestone="RC4"></milestone>
      <milestone date="06/27/2012" milestone="Juno"></milestone>
      <postamble>
      	<html:div>
			MDT MoDisco will produce maintenance releases to align with the Indigo SR releases, that includes the Eclipse Platform 3.7.1 and 3.7.2 releases.
			MDT MoDisco may produce interim maintenance releases in addition to these in order to satisfy client requests.
			<html:ul>
     			<html:li>Friday, September 23, 2012 - MDT MoDisco 0.9.1 maintenance release (Indigo Service Release 1)</html:li>
     			<html:li>Friday, February 24, 2012 - MDT MoDisco 0.9.2 maintenance release (Indigo Service Release 2)</html:li>
     		</html:ul>
		</html:div>
	  </postamble>
   </release_milestones>
   <target_environments>
     <html:div>
     	In order to remain current, each Eclipse release targets reasonably current versions of the underlying operating environments. 
     	The Eclipse MDT MoDisco project depends upon on the Platform and other projects, which are mostly "pure" Java. 
     	The 3.8 and 4.2 releases of the Eclipse Platform Project are written and compiled against version 5.0 of the Java Platform APIs, and targeted to run on version 5.0 of the Java Runtime Environment, Standard Edition. 
     	MDT MoDisco will target the same Java version as EMF, which currently also requires Java 5. 
     	Eclipse Platform SDK 3.8 and 4.2 will be tested and validated on a number of reference platforms. 
     	MDT MoDisco will be tested and validated against a subset of those listed for the platform.
     </html:div>
     <internationalization>
          <html:div>
         	 The Eclipse Platform is designed as the basis for internationalized products. 
         	 The user interface elements provided by the Eclipse SDK components, including dialogs and error messages, are externalized. 
         	 The English strings are provided as the default resource bundles. 
         	 As a result, the MDT MoDisco project will provide English strings in its default bundles and be localized to a subset of those locales offered by the Platform.
          </html:div>
     </internationalization>
   </target_environments>
   <compatibility_with_previous_releases>
   		<html:div>
       		Compatibility of Release 0.10.0: The MDT MoDisco project will be developed in parallel, and released simultaneously, with the following Eclipse projects. 
       		As stated above, each milestone release of the MDT MoDisco project will be compatible with the corresponding milestones for each of these projects, and delivered the appropriate offset.
       		<html:ul>
     			<html:li>Platform SDK version 3.8 (or 4.2)</html:li>
     			<html:li>Eclipse Modeling Framework (EMF) version 2.7.0</html:li>
     			<html:li>EMF Connected Data Objects (CDO) version 4.1.0</html:li>
     			<html:li>EMF Compare version 1.2.1</html:li>
     			<html:li>EMF Query version 1.2.1</html:li>
     			<html:li>EMF Validation version 1.4.0</html:li>
     			<html:li>EMFT EMF Facet version 0.2.0</html:li>
     			<html:li>MDT UML2 version 4.0.0</html:li>
     			<html:li>MDT OCL version 3.2.0</html:li>
     			<html:li>M2M ATL version 3.2.1</html:li>
     			<html:li>M2T Acceleo version 3.1.1</html:li>
     			<html:li>Technology SWTBot version 2.0.4</html:li>
     			<html:li>Eclipse Business Intelligence and Reporting Tools (BIRT) version 3.7.1</html:li>
     		</html:ul>
       	</html:div>
   </compatibility_with_previous_releases>
   <themes_and_priorities>
     <preamble>
         <html:div>
         	A list of project requirements and agreed upon implementation time frames is found in this document. 
         	For the milestones listed in this document, a set of overall themes is used to indicate what major set of functionalities is to be concentrated on for each. 
         	These themes are presented below, while the requirements document and associated Bugzilla entries are left to those wanting more detailed information on each. 
         </html:div>
     </preamble>
	 <theme name="Restructuring">
        <description>
        	<html:div>
        		The MDT MoDisco project will be subject to some internal restructuring (already in progress) for several of its components to be finally migrated to the EMFT EMF Facet project.
        		This migration will notably concern the Query Manager and Facet Manager components, parts of the Infrastructure layer.
				This theme is a priority to provide a stable release to all MoDisco users. That is why non critical bugs (e.g., bugs concerning the other themes) will be fixed afterwards.
			</html:div>
        </description>
        <!-- 
        <committed bugzilla=""/>
      	<proposed bugzilla=""/>
      	<deferred bugzilla=""/>
     	-->
     </theme>
	 <theme name="Scalability">
        <description>
        	<html:div>
        		The MDT MoDisco project will be subject to several upgrades directly related to the improvement of scalability for its different components.
        		This will include the increase of global performances (in terms of CPU time, memory footprint, etc), but also the more advanced support for (very) big EMF models.     
			</html:div>
        </description>
        <!-- 
        <committed bugzilla=""/>
      	<proposed bugzilla=""/>
      	<deferred bugzilla=""/>
     	-->
     </theme>
	 <theme name="Service, Support and Maintenance (general project and Infrastructure layer)">
        <description>
        	<html:div>
        		The MDT MoDisco project has a proven track record of quality and reliability. 
        		After restructuring, service and support will take priority over new development work; commitments and schedules are subject to arbitrary change, slippage, or even deferral.
			</html:div>
        </description>
        <!-- 
        <committed bugzilla=""/>
      	<proposed bugzilla=""/>
      	<deferred bugzilla=""/>
      	-->
     </theme>
     <theme name="Service, Support and Maintenance (Technologies and Use Cases layers)">
        <description>
        	<html:div>
        		The MDT MoDisco project has a proven track record of quality and reliability. 
        		After restructuring, service and support will take priority over new development work; commitments and schedules are subject to arbitrary change, slippage, or even deferral.   
			</html:div>
        </description> 
        <!--
        <committed bugzilla=""/>
      	<proposed bugzilla=""/>
      	<deferred bugzilla=""/>
      	-->
     </theme>
     <!--
     <postamble>
     	<html:div>
        </html:div>	
     </postamble>
     -->
   </themes_and_priorities>
   <appendix name="Legal Notices">
   	 <html:div>
     	<html:ul>
     		<html:li>Java is a trademark or a registered trademark of Oracle and Sun, Inc.</html:li>
     		<html:li>UML is trademark or registered trademark of the Object Management Group, Inc.</html:li>
     		<html:li>JEE is trademark or registered trademark of Oracle and Sun, Inc.</html:li>
     		<html:li>All other products or company names are mentioned for identification purposes only, and may be trademarks or service marks of their respective owners.</html:li>
     	</html:ul>	
     </html:div>  
   </appendix>	
 </plan>